Esta lição 30 de PEMSLO Inglês 1. Rosa and Charles
are in a restaurant. Listen to this conversation.
Tell me, Rosa, how long are you going to stay in New York?
For a few days. I don't have much time.
Do you like New York? Yes, I do. I like New
York very much. What are you going to do tomorrow?
Tomorrow I'm going to see some friends. Listen again.
Tell me, Rosa, how long are you going to stay in New York?
For a few days. I don't have much time. Do you
like New York? Yes, I do. I like New York very much.
What are you going to do tomorrow? Tomorrow I'm going to see some friends.
Ask in English. Como vai?
How are you?
Answer: Bem, obrigado. E você?
Fine, thanks. And you?
I'm fine,
thanks. And you?
Say: Nada mal.
Not bad. Not bad.
How do you say palavra?
Word.
Word. Ask o que
isso quer dizer?
What does that mean?
What does that word mean?
That word.
Note que that também quer dizer essa.
Pergunte outra vez o que quer dizer essa palavra.
What does that word mean?
That word.
Say that it's an English word.
It's an English word.
Now try to ask, como se diz?
Literalmente, como você diz?
How do you say?
How do you
say?
Say essa palavra.
That word.
Try to ask. Como se diz essa palavra?
How do you say that word?
Try to say English.
In English. In English.
Ask, como se diz essa palavra em inglês?
How do
you say that word in English?
Say again. Nada mal.
Not bad. Now say,
nós somos brasileiros.
We're Brazilian.
Try to say, nós gostamos da América.
We like America.
We like.
Ask in English. Quanto tempo?
How long?
Quanto tempo faz que vocês estão aqui?
How long have you been here?
Answer: algumas semanas.
A few weeks. A few
weeks.
Nós estamos aqui faz algumas semanas.
We've been here for a few weeks.
And how do you say? Nós estamos aqui desde ontem.
We've been here since yesterday.
Yesterday.
Since yesterday. Nós vamos ficar.
We're going to stay.
Por alguns dias.
For a few days.
Ask quantos dias.
How many days?
Answer: Two days.
Two days. We're going
to stay for two days.
Nós não temos muito tempo.
We don't have much time.
Ask her if she likes New York. Ask her if she likes
New York.
Do you like New York?
Say, "Não é nada mau." It's
not bad.
It's not bad.
Now say, "Vocês vão ficar." You're
going to stay.
You're going to stay.
Quanto tempo?
How long? How long?
Usando o número, diga uma semana.
One week.
Say again. Nós estamos aqui desde ontem.
We've been here since yesterday.
Now ask. O que você fez ontem?
What did you do yesterday?
É assim que se pergunta. Você comprou algo?
Listen and repeat. Did you buy anything?
Anything?
Did you buy anything?
Note que se diz anything porque você está se referindo
a qualquer coisa. How do you ask? Você comprou
algo? Did you buy anything?
Did you buy anything?
Ask. O que você comprou?
What did you buy?
Ask. Você comprou
um jornal americano?
Did you buy an American newspaper?
An American newspaper?
Answer. Eu comprei.
I bought.
Muitas coisas. Listen and repeat. A lot of
things. Things.
Things.
A lot of things.
Ask again. Você comprou algo?
Did you buy anything?
Sim, eu comprei muitas coisas.
Yes, I bought a lot of things.
Eu comprei um jornal americano.
I bought an American newspaper.
An American newspaper.
Para meu marido. For my
husband. Say,
eu comprei um jornal para ele.
I bought a newspaper for him.
For him. Usando some,
diga, eu comprei café.
And I bought some coffee.
Para minha amiga Mary.
For my friend Mary.
Eu comprei café para ela.
I bought some coffee for her.
For her. I bought some coffee
for her.
Ask, e você? And you?
O que você fez ontem?
What did you do yesterday?
Ask. Você comprou algo?
Did you buy anything?
Anything. Você comprou
algo para sua esposa?
Did you buy anything for your wife?
Ask him if he bought a lot of things.
Did you buy a lot of things?
Você comprou algo para ela?
Did you buy anything for her?
For her?
Escute e repita sua resposta negativa breve.
No, I didn't.
Now say, eu não preciso de nada.
I don't need anything.
Eu não quero nada.
I don't want anything.
Nós não queremos nada.
We don't want anything.
Nós não queremos comprar nada.
We don't want to buy anything.
Try to say, nós não vamos comprar nada.
We're not going to buy anything.
E vocês?
And you?
Vocês compraram algo?
Did you buy anything?
Nós estamos aqui desde ontem.
We've been here since yesterday.
E nós compramos muitas coisas.
And we bought a lot of things.
Quando?
When? Ontem. Yesterday.
Yesterday. É assim que
se diz vocês chegaram. Listen and repeat.
You arrived.
Arrived.
Arrived. You arrived.
Você pronunciou o som d ao final de arrived.
Diga outra vez: Vocês chegaram.
You arrived.
Agora, vocês chegaram? Listen and repeat
again. Did you arrive?
Did arrive?
Did you arrive?
Now try to ask. Quando vocês chegaram?
When did you arrive?
Nós chegamos ontem. Listen and repeat.
We arrived yesterday.
Arrived.
Repita o par de palavras depois da locutora.
Did arrive, arrived.
Say again. Nós chegamos ontem.
We arrived yesterday.
Ela acrescenta ontem de manhã. Listen and repeat.
Yesterday morning.
Morning. Yesterday morning.
Say again. Ontem de manhã.
Yesterday morning.
Morning. Ask again. Quando vocês chegaram?
When did you arrive?
Now try to ask. Quando vocês chegaram em Nova York?
When did you arrive in New York?
In New York.
Say, nós chegamos ontem.
We arrived yesterday.
Ask again. Quando vocês chegaram em Nova York?
When did you arrive in New York?
Nós chegamos ontem de manhã.
We arrived yesterday morning.
Try to say: Eu cheguei.
I arrived.
I arrived. Eu cheguei
em Nova York.
I arrived in New York.
In New York. Com minha
família.
With my family.
Com meus três filhos.
With my three children.
E meu marido.
And my husband.
And my
husband. Ask,
a que horas? At what
time?
Answer, nós chegamos às oito.
We arrived at eight o'clock.
Ask, e você?
And you? Quando você
chegou em Nova York?
When did you arrive in New York?
Answer: Eu cheguei ontem de manhã.
I arrived yesterday morning.
Às nove.
At nine o'clock.
Ask. E quando vocês chegaram na América?
And when did you arrive in America?
Aqui está uma outra maneira de dizer América: os
Estados Unidos. Listen and repeat. The United
States.
United. United.
United States.
The United
States.
How do you say Os Estados Unidos.
The United States.
Try to ask: Quando vocês chegaram nos Estados Unidos?
When did you arrive in the United States? In the
United States.
Answer: Nós chegamos ontem de manhã.
We arrived yesterday morning.
How do you say "Amanhã"?
Tomorrow. Tomorrow.
Try to say "Amanhã de manhã." Tomorrow
morning.
Tomorrow morning.
Now try to say. Nós vamos embora amanhã
We are leaving tomorrow morning.
Nós vamos ficar.
We're going to stay.
Por uma semana. Use your number for
one week. Ask her if she
likes the United States.
Do you like the United States?
Say that yes, you do.
Yes, I do.
Yes, we do.
We like the United States.
Mas nós não temos muito tempo.
But we don't have much time.
Nós vamos embora.
We're leaving. Amanhã de
manhã. Tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow morning.
Ask her if she bought anything.
Did you buy anything?
Escute e repita sua resposta. Yes,
I did. Yes,
I did. Ask her
what she bought.
What did you buy?
Answer: Um jornal americano.
An American newspaper.
E muitas coisas.
And a lot of things.
Para meu marido.
For my husband. Eu comprei
muitas coisas para ele.
I bought a lot of things for him.
Try to say: nós gostamos dos Estados Unidos.
We like the United States.
Mas nós vamos embora amanhã de manhã.
But we're leaving tomorrow morning.
Este é o final da lição 30 e o final de Inglês 1.